Guide to the Herman F. Mark Collection RG.002
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
- Series VIII: Framed photographs and documents
  - Subseries C: Needs Conservation
    - ICRFS (International Conference on Research Frontiers in Sciences), Undated; cuid3463 (Bin Cart)
    - Framed medal from Republic of France, Undated; cuid3464 (Bin Cart)
    - The Society of the Sigma XI of the Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn 1970, cuid3465 (Bin Cart)
    - 90th Birthday Plaque from Graduate Students in Chemistry 1985, cuid3466 (Bin Cart)
    - Circular mirror, Undated; cuid3467 (Bin Cart)
    - Blue fringe hat, Undated; cuid3468 (Bin Cart)
    - Box full of photograph slides, Undated; cuid3469 (Bin Cart)
    - Polymer Paperweight, Undated; cuid3470 (Bin Cart)
    - Wooden clock with world map, Undated; cuid3471 (Bin Cart)
    - Gold metal clock, Undated; cuid3472 (Bin Cart)
- Series IX: Magnetic Media
  - Subseries A: Video tapes: Interviews and Ceremonies
    - American Chemical Society Interview with Dr. Herman F. Mark, Dr. Charles Overberger, interviewer (part 1 of 2), 1981; cuid3349; Umatic tape (Box 25, Object 1)
    - American Chemical Society Interview with Dr. Herman F. Mark, Dr. Charles Overberger, interviewer (part 2 of 2), 1981; cuid3350; Umatic tape (Box 25, Object 2)
    - Eminent Chemists: H. Mark Interviewed by C. Overberger (part 1 of 2), undated; cuid3351; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 3)
    - Eminent Chemists Videotape Series: Dr. Herman F. Mark, undated; cuid3352; U-matic Runtime 46:10 (Box 25, Object 4)
      To view the digitized video, contact the Poly Archives.
    - H. Mark Interviewed by C. Overberger (part 2 of 2), undated; cuid3353; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 5)
    - Herman Mark, undated; cuid3354; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 6)
    - Presidential Ceremony Honoring the 1979 Medal of Science Awardees, 1980 January 14; cuid3355; U-matic Run time: approximately 20 minutes (Box 25, Object 7)
  - Subseries B: Video Tapes: Polymer Research
    - The Development of Early Polymer Chemistry in America -- The Early Years: Carl S. Marvel, 1980; cuid3356; Umatic tape (Box 25, Object 8)
    - MRS - Frontiers in Materials Research: Recent Advances in Polymers - H. Mark, 1989; cuid3357; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 9)
    - Polymer Science: Visions and Perspectives 1 of 2, 1999; cuid3358; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 10)
    - Polymer Science: Visions and Perspectives 2 of 2, 1999; cuid3359; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 11)
    - H. Mark PRI [Polymer Research Institute], undated; cuid3360; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 12)
  - Subseries C: Video tapes: Scientific Topics
    - Herman Mark: Early 20th Century Physics (1), Probably 1979; cuid3361; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 13)
    - Herman Mark: Fibers (3), 1979; cuid3362; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 14)
    - Herman Mark: Rubber (4), 1979; cuid3363; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 15)
    - Herman Mark: Polymers and the Environment (5), 1979; cuid3364; VHS tapes (Box 25, Object 16)
    - Herman F. Mark: Aviation - Fire, 1983; cuid3365; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 17)
  - Subseries D: 3M Magnetic Tapes
    - Polymers Part III, 1968 March 9; cuid3366 (Box 26, Object 1)
    - H. Mark Polymers, undated; cuid3367 (Box 26, Object 2)
    - H. Mark Polymers, undated; cuid3368 (Box 26, Object 3)
  - Subseries E: Audio tapes and 740 diskettes
    - Lord Corporation's Symposium tapes, 1989 October 3-4; cuid3369 (Box 26, Object 4)
    - "Dimensions in Science" American Chemical Society, circa 1985; cuid3370 (Box 26, Object 5)
    - Mark II, undated; cuid3371 (Box 26, Object 6)
    - Mark III, undated; cuid3372 (Box 26, Object 7)
    - Unlabeled, undated; cuid3373 (Box 26, Object 8)
    - H. Mark 740 diskette (Scotch 3M), undated; cuid3374 (Box 26, Object 9)
    - Mark 740 diskette (IBM), undated; cuid3375 (Box 26, Object 10)
    - Chemistry Mark 740 diskette (IBM), undated; cuid3376 (Box 26, Object 11)
- Series X: Personal items and Miscellaneous
  - Subseries A: Desk drawer realia
    - Portable 3-Dimensional Joke Kit (actually contains spices), undated; cuid3377 (Box 27, Object 1)
    - Fulton Rubber Type Outift, undated; cuid3378 (Box 27, Object 2)
    - ABC rubber stamp kit, undated; cuid3379 (Box 27, Object 3)
    - North America Steel Company magnifying glass, cuid3380 (Box 27, Object 4)
    - Set of three keys, undated; cuid3381 (Box 27, Object 5)
    - Set of two key fobs with "Dr. H Mark", undated; cuid3382 (Box 27, Object 6)
    - Plastic cylinder, undated; cuid3383 (Box 27, Object 7)
    - Plastic in petri dish labeled "Hema", undated; cuid3384 (Box 27, Object 8)
    - Birthday candles and holders, undated; cuid3385 (Box 27, Object 9)
    - Calculator, undated; cuid3386 (Box 27, Object 10)
    - Metal pieces in envelope, undated; cuid3387 (Box 27, Object 11)
    - Cologne, undated; cuid3388 (Box 27, Object 12)
    - Polarizing film, undated; cuid3389 (Box 27, Object 13)
    - Three beakers, undated; cuid3390 (Box 27, Object 14)
    - Buttons in envelope, undated; cuid3391 (Box 27, Object 15)
    - Oxford copy holder, undated; cuid3392 (Box 27, Object 16)
    - Magnifying glass, undated; cuid3393 (Box 27, Object 17)
  - Subseries B: Personal, financial and medical records
    - Personal (contains bank statements, correspondence, memberships), circa 1991-1992; cuid3394 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Personal 1990, cuid3395 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Condolences, 1992; cuid3396 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Symposium, regrets, 1989; cuid3397 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Mark Estate, 1992; cuid3398 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Bank statements, 1992; cuid3399 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Payments, 1992, cuid3400 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Receipts, 1992, cuid3401 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Tax forms and bank statements, 1991-1992; cuid3402 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Rents, 1990, cuid3403 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Taxes, 1989-1991, cuid3404 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Work sheets, 1988, cuid3405 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Bank statements, 1988, cuid3406 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Payments, 1988, cuid3407 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Receipts, 1988, cuid3408 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Receipts, January-April 1988, cuid3409 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Receipts, May-August 1988, cuid3410 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Receipts, September-December 1988, cuid3411 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Receipts, 1987, cuid3412 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous receipts, 1981-1990; undated; cuid3413 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Medical, 1990-1992; cuid3414 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Medicare, 1989-1991; cuid3415 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Subseries C: Miscellaneous
    - Air clubs, 1978-1992; cuid3416 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Maps and train timetables, undated; cuid3417 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Magazines, 1998; cuid3418 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous documents and publications, undated; cuid3419 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous documents, undated; cuid3420 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous notes, undated; cuid3421 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Numbered ink drawing, undated; cuid3422 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Herman Mark's suitcase (containing shirt, tie, and sweater), undated; cuid3423 (Box unboxed)
    - Herman Mark's leather tote bag, undated; cuid3424 (Box unboxed)
- Series XI: Collection provenance and information
  - Austrian National Library, 1992; cuid3425 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Herman Mark Collection (Heather Walters), 2001; cuid3426 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Herman Mark Collection (Lindsay Anderberg, Hans Mark, Jana Richman), 2013-2014; cuid3427 (Box 29, Folder 7)
- Series XII: Objects that Need Conservation
  Accruals
  Tentative series of miscellaneous objects that belonged to Mark that require conservation.
  These miscellaneous items are housed in 7 boxes on bay 33 shelves 7B, 6A and 7A.
  - Resin/Enamel Rectangular Paperweight, undated; cuid3562 (Box 40, Object 1)
  - Framed CIRFS Medal, undated; cuid3565 (Box 40, Object 2)
  - Swiss Clock, undated; cuid3567 (Box 40, Object 3)
  - Circular Mirror, undated; cuid3568 (Box 41, Object 1)
  - Framed 'Republique Française' Medal, undated; cuid3563 (Box 42, Object 1)
  - 90th Birthday Plaque, 1985-11; cuid3564 (Box 42, Object 2)
  - General Electric World Clock, undated; cuid3569 (Box 43, Object 1)
  - Sigma Xi Award, 1970-06-02; cuid3571 (Box 44, Object 1)
  - Ceremonial Hat, undated; cuid3566 (Box 45, Object 1)
  - New Years Lantern Slides, undated; cuid3570 (Box 46, Object 1)